<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Alex Levis</title>
        <link>https://alexlevis.github.io/</link>
        <description>Welcome!</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>alex.w.levis@gmail.com (Alex Levis)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>alex.w.levis@gmail.com (Alex Levis)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://alexlevis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>To adjust or not to adjust: instruments and precision variables</title>
    <link>https://alexlevis.github.io/instrument-precision/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Levis</author>
    <guid>https://alexlevis.github.io/instrument-precision/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently, I&rsquo;ve been listening to (i.e., binging) the Casual Inference podcast hosted by Lucy D&rsquo;Agostino McGowan and Ellie Murrary, and a question was raised at least a couple of times (Season 3 Episode 10 &amp; Season 4 Episode 9): does adjusting for an instrument (in, e.g., a propensity score model) cause bias? I believe the answer to this question is no, except in somewhat extreme scenarios. However, such a choice will impact the efficiency of a treatment effect estimator.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>MGFs, power series, and pushing the expectation through</title>
    <link>https://alexlevis.github.io/mgf-bounds/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Levis</author>
    <guid>https://alexlevis.github.io/mgf-bounds/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I got stuck on what I thought was a simple point while working through a stats textbook! I figured it out, I think, but was this the most straightforward path to understanding? You tell me! In this note, we explore some oft-used facts about moment-generating functions, and explain a connection with tail and concentration inequalities.
Overview and my confusion I am currently reading through Martin Wainwright&rsquo;s High-dimensional statistics: A non-asymptotic viewpoint, to fill some gaps in my stat theory knowledge.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
