<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Alex Levis</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Alex Levis</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>alex.w.levis@gmail.com (Alex Levis)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>alex.w.levis@gmail.com (Alex Levis)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>To adjust or not to adjust: instruments and precision variables</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/instrument-precision/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Levis</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/instrument-precision/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently, I&rsquo;ve been listening to (i.e., binging) the Casual Inference podcast hosted by Lucy D&rsquo;Agostino McGowan and Ellie Murrary, and a question was raised at least a couple of times (Season 3 Episode 10 &amp; Season 4 Episode 9): does adjusting for an instrument (in, e.g., a propensity score model) cause bias? I believe the answer to this question is no, except in somewhat extreme scenarios. However, such a choice will impact the efficiency of a treatment effect estimator.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>An introduction to instrumental variables</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/iv-intro/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Levis</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/iv-intro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/iv-dag.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A focus of my postdoctoral research is on using instrumental variables for causal inference. There is a large literature in economics and epidemiology on this topic, but much of the terminology is scattered, and the underlying causal and statistical frameworks vary from place to place. My goal in this post is to give an overview of the salient features of an instrumental variable (IV), and discuss broadly when (and perhaps how) IVs can be used to aid in causal inference research.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Causality, counterfactuals, confounding</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/causal-intro/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Levis</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/causal-intro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/confounding-dag.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In introductory statistics courses, one often encounters the phrase: &ldquo;correlation does not imply causation.&rdquo; As a statistician who studies causality, I would amend this phrase to say: &ldquo;correlation does not necessarily imply causation, but it can.&rdquo; In this post, I introduce a framework for bridging the worlds of statistics and causality, and talk about when and how we can quantify so-called causal effects from data observed in the real world.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>MGFs, power series, and pushing the expectation through</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mgf-bounds/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Alex Levis</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/mgf-bounds/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I got stuck on what I thought was a simple point while working through a stats textbook! I figured it out, I think, but was this the most straightforward path to understanding? You tell me! In this note, we explore some oft-used facts about moment-generating functions, and explain a connection with tail and concentration inequalities.
Overview and my confusion I am currently reading through Martin Wainwright&rsquo;s High-dimensional statistics: A non-asymptotic viewpoint, to fill some gaps in my stat theory knowledge.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
